Will we find it?
I'm sure we will.
-I'm pretty sure.
-It's so fun.
There's a lot. We've seen them before.
Yeah.
We found a lot.
Yeah, a lot.
Your bug cage is so small.
This cage?
It won't fit in there.
-You think so?
-No worries.
Just one is enough anyway.
You're right.
I don't want it to be too small though.
Just a little farther.
-Junichi.
-Yeah?
Let's go this way.
What?
-This way?
-Yeah.
It's closer that way.
No, this way is closer.
This way is dangerous.
The other route worked last time.
Just choose which way is best.
Let's split into two groups.
Only Keisuke and I know the route.
Which way do you want to go, Maki?
‎NO TRESPASSING
Let's do rock, paper, scissors.
Rock, paper, scissors.
I'm paper.
You and me, Naoto.
All right, let's go!
What?
Wait for me.
-Hurry up, Naoto.
-Wait.
-Naoto.
-Sorry.
Naoto.
What should we do if we meet the culprit?
The one on the run.
That bank robber, with a gun.
We won't run into the robber.
What if, by some chance,
we run into the culprit?
I'll protect you.
I see…
-Are you okay?
-Ouch.
Thanks.
Hey.
Hm?
Have you kissed anyone before?
What?
-Stop!
-Ouch!
Are you serious?
It's your fault for fooling around.
What was that?
What was that--
That day,
the four of us committed a crime.
The crime we committed
was sealed away in a time capsule
that would never be opened in the future.
It's been 23 years since then.
I never saw them again.
Riichi.
Already?
MITSUBA POLICE
Hello, it's Tobina.
Hey, where are you right now?
Well, right now I'm…
Mr. Kamata in Mikoto-cho
is complaining again,
so could you go and check on him?
He specifically asked for you.
I'm off duty right now.
Someone reported you guys to the police.
Shut up.
Hello.
Hello there.
-What's going on?
-It's that old man.
This way.
Try to keep it down.
Shut up.
Mr. Kamata. Hello.
They're so loud.
-Are you all right?
-Their motorcycle is so loud.
Why don't you tell me what happened
-while we play a game of shogi?
-Sounds great.
-Let's go.
-Yeah.
Are you serious?
That's insane.
You were off-duty, but got called in
when it's not even a major incident?
It just means things are peaceful.
But still, what if you were on a date,
or in a situation where you didn't
want to leave?
You've got a point.
I was so close to winning a good hand.
What do you mean?
Nothing shady, I hope.
-Hello.
-What are you talking about?
You've completely blended in,
in the two months you've been here.
-Captain.
-Yeah?
I just sent you my report.
-Okay.
-Please review it.
Mr. Tobina, you used to live
in this town, right?
Until sixth grade.
Really?
Do you have friends that still live here?
I haven't seen them at all
since I graduated.
Really?
You haven't even
run into them around town?
Nope.
You might not notice them
even if you ran into them.
It's been over 20 years, right?
-It's been 23 years.
-Wow.
That's crazy.
Do you remember the girl
you liked in elementary school?
Be honest. I don't remember at all.
-Bye.
Stop!
Ouch.
Are you serious?
It's your fault for fooling around.
-Welcome.
-Hi.
-Thank you.
-Thank you as always.
Likewise.
Your hair has gotten longer.
You think so?
Masaki got accepted.
To Hamadai Middle School?
No way! That's awesome!
That's great, Maki! Congratulations!
Clam down, Naoto.
But it's great news.
Both you and Masaki worked
so hard for this moment.
Thank you.
Speaking of Masaki…
-Hey there.
-Hello.
-Can you hold this for me?
-Sure.
Thank you.
Congratulations on your acceptance
into Hamadai Middle School.
Thank you.
So happy for you.
There's cake here.
-Cake?
-Mr. Naoto brought it.
-Wow.
-Thanks.
THE DAYS OF MARKING TIME
WILL COME TO AN END
AND A NEW CHAPTER WILL BEGIN
MAKIKO
Hello.
Keisuke?
When can you come over here?
Let's see…
You didn't come back last month either.
Sorry.
I'm okay, but I'm thinking about Masaki.
You did promise to meet him
once a month, after all.
Sorry, I haven't even had time
to sleep lately.
I'm still in the office as we speak.
I see.
Well, try to take it easy.
Instead of taking an hour and a half
to come here,
I'd rather have you get some rest.
I'll go there once things
settle down here.
I want to celebrate Masaki's
school acceptance too.
Yeah.
Later.
Bye.
Nice, Junichi.
Very nice.
Good job, Maki.
Good job, Naoto. Go.
Very good.
Meditation!
SMILE SAKUMA
-Thank you.
-I'll come again.
-We'll be waiting.
Hello, this is Ma saison.
Where is Makiko Iwamoto?
Is she there?
She's with a client right now.
If you'd like to make an appointment,
I can do that for you.
Makiko Iwamoto.
Manager.
Yeah.
Um…
The caller keeps repeating,
"Makiko Iwamoto."
Hello, this is the manager,
Iwamoto, speaking.
Long time no see.
It's Sakuma.
-Excuse me, but…
-Can you come here right away?
To Smile Sakuma.
What?
Um…
Do you finally remember
who I am?
I'm not sure what this is regarding,
but I'm currently assisting
another client.
His name is Masaki, huh?
Your son, I mean.
Why do you know about Masaki?
Your son
shoplifted from my store.
NAOTO
The person you have called
cannot answer the phone right now.
SMILE SAKUMA
Ms. Iwamoto!
Hello.
It's unusual to see you here
at this time of the day.
Is your shop closed?
No, it's open today.
I see. You know,
it's taking so long
for my bangs to grow out.
But there's an event coming up
so I'm trying to grow them out.
Please do my hair again.
Of course, any time.
Do you finally remember
who I am?
Sorry for taking you away from work.
I sincerely apologize for the trouble
my son has caused.
Come inside.
Where's my son?
I have him waiting somewhere else.
We can't let him overhear
the conversation between adults, right?
Don't worry.
This is my personal office.
This thing
is 330 yen.
I'm very sorry.
He's still just a kid.
There's no need to make a big fuss
over something as minor as shoplifting.
Some people might think like that,
but shoplifting is still a serious crime.
Besides, I'm the store manager here.
I have a certain position to uphold.
I can refrain
from reporting this to the police.
I'll even give you this video footage.
That is,
if you show me your sincerity.
Sincerity?
Okay. Roger.
There was a report of a break-in
at a residence.
The culprit is still at the scene.
Tobina…
and…
Nagai.
Head to the scene.
Awesome!
Yes!
It's been a while
since we dealt with a culprit!
Mr. Tobina, I'll bring the car around!
Mitsuko.
Mitsuko!
Who needs those useless wings?
He's a complete stranger.
When I came home, he was watching TV
like he owned the place.
Who's that on the bed?
My mom!
-I'll go inside.
-Okay.
Hey dear,
next time he forgets something,
let's not take it to him anymore.
It won't do any good.
Nagai.
Yes.
Hello.
"Mr. Yoshihiko Nakamura."
"Specialized Nursing Home."
"Chitose-en, Irohadai."
Hello, Mr. Nakamura.
Hello.
OPPOSE THE CONSTRUCTION
OF THE SHOPPING MALL!
-Nagai.
-Yeah?
What's that?
It's an elementary school
that closed down.
That's where I went.
Seriously? That's crazy.
There're plans for a building complex,
and the residents are staging
a protest against it.
A building complex?
A community center
and a large-scale shopping mall.
It will be built by Mitsuba City
and Sakuma Land Development.
Sakuma is a big name around here.
They run the supermarket Smile Sakuma.
That guy just now…
the manager of this store,
is Naoto's older brother.
He decided to let us go this time.
But promise me
that you'll never do this again.
Do you understand what you've done?
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
It's okay now.
Thank you for coming all the way here.
How's Masaki?
He's in bed already.
Did you get in touch with Naoto?
No.
I think he'll contact me
once he reads my message.
You're meeting up with him tonight
at 11:00 p.m., right?
Yeah.
Hey,
are you seriously going to comply
with his demand?
There's no other option.
Do you think someone
who's demanding 300,000 yen
will stop with just this once?
He's going to give me
the security video footage.
He can make copies of that.
Then what do you suggest we do?
He says he'll report our son to the police
if we don't pay him 300,000 yen.
Even if Masaki is reported
for shoplifting,
the police can't do anything about it.
He's only 12 years old.
What if his school finds out?
Can you guarantee that his admission
to middle school won't be revoked?
Well…
I guess there's a chance
of that getting revoked.
There are tons of other middle schools.
It's not that simple.
You don't get it, Keisuke.
Do you have any idea how much I struggled
to secure that highly recommended school?
Either way,
there's no other choice
but to buy his silence.
If that's what you want,
then I'll pay the 300,000--
It's okay.
I already went to the bank
and withdrew the money.
I'll go with you.
-What?
-I'll talk to him.
I'll make him sign a written agreement.
If he accepts the money,
it will be considered extortion.
He's the one who will be in trouble
if the police get involved.
Okay.
Thank you.
Masaki.
I'm coming in.
I'm Masaki's father.
You didn't come alone.
Where's the money?
Let's talk first.
No, hand me the money first.
Unless you want me to cancel this deal.
Whoa.
Wow.
I want written confirmation
of this exchange,
-and hand over the security footage.
-Now, now,
just slow down.
Let's have a chat. Man to man.
SMILE SAKUMA
NAOTO SAKUMA
SORRY FOR THE SUDDEN CALL
ARE YOU BUSY? CAN WE TALK?
I NEED TO TALK TO YOU.
MASAKI SHOPLIFTED
FROM YOUR BROTHER'S SHOP.
How was it?
Sorry.
What?
Just as I thought, he won't end things
with 300,000 yen,
and he didn't give me the footage either.
He said if we don't
do as he says tomorrow,
he'll report it to Masaki's school.
We shouldn't let him manipulate us
any further.
What is he asking for now?
JANUARY 17TH
What time is it?
It's past seven.
Your night shift finally ended?
I'm so sleepy.
It's tough working as a nurse.
I can fall asleep in ten seconds.
Good night.
-You're leaving already?
-Yeah.
Being a detective is tough too, huh?
-Bye.
-I'll be off.
I messaged Naoto and left a voicemail too.
But he hasn't contacted me yet.
I called Naoto's workplace.
Sakuma Land Development?
Yeah.
Our design team is handling
Naoto's project,
and I'm involved as an architect.
The huge supermarket
that's going to be built
on the old school site?
Yeah, that one.
What? You're part of that project?
Naoto didn't mention it at all.
And what happened when you called?
He's on a business trip to Korea
and will be returning to Haneda
before 9:00 p.m. tonight.
Before 9:00 p.m., okay.
Hey.
You're really doing this?
Yes, I'm going to comply with his demand.
I'm going to protect Masaki
no matter what.
Okay.
We're meeting him at 11:00 p.m., right?
I'll go check-in at the hotel once.
I want to shower too.
You're not returning to Tokyo today?
I'm staying here tonight.
You can stay at my place.
Oh…
well, um…
I can expense it anyway.
Then
I'll go back to my shop.
You should at least come over for dinner.
Oh…
I bet you're eating unhealthy things
since you're on your own.
It's been a while,
so let's have a meal with Masaki.
Hey.
I have a lot of work to do today,
so I'll be staying overnight.
Okay.
How are you feeling? Still doing okay?
I'm okay.
What about you, Keisuke?
Call me if you need me.
Bye.
Yes, thank you. Goodbye.
This is where it was all along?
I'm sorry,
but I need to talk to you about something.
Masaki shoplifted
from your older brother's supermarket.
I'll be off.
I think I should go too--
You shouldn't come.
SMILE SAKUMA
Good morning.
I'm going to begin the morning Smile Sale.
Manager, I'm taking the key.
You're not here?
IGAWA
Manager.
Chief, good morning.
Good morning!
The murdered victim
is said to be the son
of the Sakuma Land Development Company.
The oldest son, not the second son.
-Okay.
-No way.
It's a big case.
The Prefectural Police's First Division
will be coming and setting up.
But it's under our jurisdiction.
Please do your best.
Yes, sir!
Yes, sir.
-Let's go.
-We'll be off.
VICTIM
Captain, your handwriting is insane.
Maybe you should have someone else
do the writing.
I'm the one who's going to write
on this board! Shut your mouth!
Heave-ho.
Thanks.
Captain is fired up.
It's been decades since we've had
a murder case like this.
I never thought we'd have
a command center set up here.
You seem happy.
I'm nervous
to be paired up with a detective
from the First Division.
Let's do this.
MURDER INVESTIGATION OF
THE NISHIMATSU-CHO SUPERMARKET MANAGER
I'm the captain
of Kanagawa First Division.
My name is Shirakawa.
I'm Kosugi,
the chief of Mitsuba Police Station.
I will be heading this investigation.
The victim has been identified
as Hideyuki Sakuma, 40 years old.
The manager of Smile Sakuma
in Mitsuba Minami.
The crime scene was the manager's office
on the store premises.
It was a space
used exclusively by the victim.
The body was first discovered
by a supermarket employee.
Shortly after 9:00 a.m., the employee
went to the manager's office
to borrow the key to the safe
and discovered the body there.
It appears he was shot
and killed with a handgun,
but the weapon has not yet been found.
The Sakuma family is known as one of
the most prominent families in the area.
The current head of the family,
and the father
of the victim, Hideyuki,
is Hidemasa Sakuma,
and he is currently hospitalized.
Last year,
he suffered a stroke
and hasn't been discharged yet.
It is said that the family business
is effectively being run
by his second son, Naoto Sakuma,
who is the managing director
of Sakuma Land Development.
What was the victim doing
the day he was killed?
Tobina.
Tobina, your partner will be Ms. Nara.
Apparently,
she's the odd one out
in the prefectural police force.
-Your voice is so loud. Shush.
-Yes, sir.
Nagai, you team up with Mr. Murakami.
The one who's talking right now.
Understood.
-Sasakura is…
-Shush.
We are from
the Kanagawa Prefectural Police.
We have come to speak
with the Sakuma family.
Hey Junichi, what are you doing?
Stop that.
What're you doing?
Keisuke, come and join me.
-There's a branch right there.
-I'm not doing that.
One costs tens of thousands.
Liar. He's lying, right Naoto?
What are you guys doing?
Naoto!
We're sorry!
I'm Hideyuki's younger brother.
My name is Naoto Sakuma.
I'm Nara.
I'm Tobina.
Junichi?
He was my classmate in elementary school.
I see.
I haven't seen him since graduation,
so it won't interfere
with the investigation.
‎I see.
Oh my, you've become a fine young man!
You're a detective now?
Long time no see.
I'm sorry,
but my mother isn't feeling well.
Then please take a rest.
Perhaps we can talk with you another day.
Then I will excuse myself.
Junichi, please come
-visit again when you have more time.
-Yes.
I'll welcome you
with freshly-baked madeleines.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Sorry to interrupt this nice reunion,
but we need to ask you about your brother.
Of course.
Your older brother lived here, right?
He came back two months ago and lived
in that detached house.
He wasn't living
in this spacious main house?
It's been like that ever since
we were kids.
Your brother was the son
of your dad's previous wife, right?
Yes.
After they divorced,
she lived with my brother for a few years,
but then she left him
and went off somewhere.
So my brother came to live here.
Where was your brother before he came here
two months ago?
In Tokyo.
Were you in contact with him?
We hardly kept in touch,
and I didn't even know
where he was living.
Once in a while he would contact me,
only to ask me to send him money
or something like that.
Do you know anyone who had
a grudge against your brother?
I don't know anything about my brother's
social circle.
But…
recently,
our company
has been receiving threats.
Threats?
That's troublesome.
It said that if we proceed
with the construction
of the building complex that our company
is planning,
divine punishment will befall us.
OPPOSE THE CONSTRUCTION
OF THE SHOPPING MALL!
What's this building complex?
We plan to collaborate with the city
to build a facility
that combines a community center
and a shopping mall.
I believe the person who sent the threat
is a local retailer who opposes
the construction.
If possible, we'd like to see
that letter containing the threat.
I'm sorry.
We received two threatening letters,
but we threw both of them away.
By the way,
regarding last night…
Where were you, Mr. Naoto?
I returned from my business trip to Korea.
I arrived at Haneda Airport
just before 9:00 p.m.
It usually takes about an hour
to get here by car,
but I got caught in traffic,
so I think I didn't get home
until a little before 11:00 p.m.
Could you tell me which flight
you were on?
Yes.
Please wait one moment.
It seems like
his older brother
was quite a troublemaker.
The families of victims usually exude
a palpable sense of grief,
but there was no such feeling present.
The owner of a hardware store
located next to
the scene of the crime,
said he heard what sounded like gunshots.
He stated that he heard them
shortly before 10:00 p.m.
Based on the reports from forensic experts
regarding the rigor mortis,
it's safe to conclude
that the victim was shot
shortly before 10:00 p.m.
Sir.
We contacted the victim's family,
but they have no idea
who the perpetrator might be.
However, it appears
that the victim's half-brother,
Naoto Sakuma,
had recently been receiving threats.
Sir.
Mr. Sakuma is currently
working on a project
to build a large complex, and it appears
he has been subjected to harassment
by retailers opposed to the development.
It is unclear whether it's related
to this case.
Sir.
We have new testimony from the employee
who was the first to discover the body.
The day before the incident,
an acquaintance, a hairdresser,
reportedly came to the supermarket,
but not to shop.
She apparently left with her son.
This was unusual because this hairdresser
used to frequent the store,
but hadn't been seen there recently.
Therefore, we asked the hairdresser
to come to the station tomorrow.
She's the manager
of the hair salon, Ma saison.
Ms. Makiko Iwamoto.
The first name is Makiko,
and the last name is Iwamoto.
Ms. Makiko Iwamoto.
Roger.
Regarding the bullet…
Is something the matter?
I had a classmate with that same name.
Oh my…
-You have everything?
-Yeah.
Bye.
Run, run.
-Bye.
Following Mr. Naoto Sakuma,
this would be reunion number two, huh?
Thank you for waiting.
I'm Nara.
I'm Tobina.
Thank you
for taking time out of your busy schedule
for us.
Let's get straight to the point.
We'd like to ask you some questions.
Okay.
The manager of Smile Sakuma,
Hideyuki Sakuma, was murdered.
Are you aware of that?
Yes, I saw it on the news.
On Friday evening,
you went to Smile Sakuma, right?
Yes.
What did you go there for?
My son called me to say
he had lost his wallet,
so I went to give him some money.
You have a son?
-Yes.
-Is he in elementary school?
Yes. Sixth grade.
I see. Your son called you
on his smartphone?
No, he doesn't have a smartphone.
I see.
Actually, my sister's daughter,
my niece, is in fifth grade,
and they're arguing about whether or not
she should have a smartphone.
I totally understand.
By the way,
did your son find his wallet?
Yes, he had left it at home.
-Is that right?
-Yes.
Thank you so much for coming here today.
Not at all.
That's all the questions we have
for today.
Detective Tobina.
Please see her out.
Yes.
I didn't know you became a detective.
What's up with you, Junichi?
You didn't contact me even once.
-Why are you laughing?
-Because
I totally thought
you had forgotten about me.
There's no way I'd forget you.
You didn't even blink an eye when we met.
I heard from Naoto
that you appeared before him
as a detective.
I see.
What? Is there something on my face?
You haven't changed at all.
You too, Junichi.
But man,
I was surprised to hear that you have
a child in sixth grade
and became a hairdresser.
You surprised me too.
The Junichi we grew up with
is now a detective.
It's been 23 years.
Yeah.
Where are you living right now?
Near Yokohama?
No, around here.
Since when?
Two months ago.
What?
Why are you being such a stranger?
You should've contacted me.
How could I?
I don't have your contact information.
MAKIKO IWAMOTO
Contact me any time.
Thanks.
Hey…
Yeah?
-Your name…
-Ah.
Oh?
You're wondering why I'm using
my maiden name when I have a kid?
Yes, exactly.
I got divorced.
Oh.
I see.
Oh,
I'll introduce you to my ex-husband.
Long time no see, Junichi.
What?
Keisuke?
Keisuke!
Wow.
-No way.
-How have you been?
What a surprise.
I can tell.
Reunion number three, huh.
You haven't changed.
Ms. Makiko Iwamoto
was my old classmate after all.
She was teasing me,
pretending she forgot about me.
She was always like that.
She's lying.
She is?
Ms. Makiko Iwamoto
is clearly lying.
Please elaborate.
I didn't know you became a detective.
Hello.
I understand.
We have an emergency meeting.
MITSUBA POLICE STATION
We have called you all together
as an emergency situation has come up.
Furthermore, you are strictly prohibited
from disclosing
the information I am about to share,
for any reason whatsoever.
The handling of this information,
including its potential release
to the media,
is being discussed by senior officials
of the prefectural police.
The bullet extracted from the body
of the victim, Hideyuki Sakuma,
was determined to have been fired
from New Nambu M60.
Seriously?
The New Nambu M60, the standard issue
handgun of our police force,
was the weapon used
in the murder of a civilian.
That's the shocking result we received.
That's crazy.
The handgun in question
has already been identified.
It was determined to be the handgun
of Police Officer Kazuo Kiyohara,
who died in the line of duty 23 years ago
and whose weapon
had been missing ever since.
Twenty-three years ago,
within this jurisdiction,
there was a robbery
of an armored cash transport vehicle…
YAMATO TRUST BANK ROBBERY CASE
…belonging to the Mitsuba branch
of the Yamato Trust Bank.
Stand back!
Put down that bag!
The culprit, Nobukazu Oshima,
stole 30 million yen in cash
and fled to a forest five kilometers away.
He had an encounter with Officer Kiyohara.
There,
he and Officer Kiyohara
shot each other, and both died.
Oshima is believed
to have had an accomplice, who is said
to have taken the 30 million yen
and Officer Kiyohara's gun,
but the 30 million yen and the gun
were never found
and remain unknown.
The handgun
that was lost 23 years ago was used
in the recent incident,
which is a very serious matter.
We're changing the investigation strategy.
Investigators have been mobilized
to locate and recover the murder weapon.
Further instructions
will be given at a later date.
Yes, sir.
‎Dad! Dad!
Dad!
On that day
the four of us committed a crime.
We thought we had sealed
the crime we committed in a time capsule
that would never be opened in the future.
Along with that gun.
This will be a secret
between just the four of us.
Okay?
‎You came as a detective, right?
‎Can the four of us meet together?
‎You came to confirm my story?
‎About the lie…
‎Let's open the time capsule.
‎We hid the gun that caused
‎headlines back in the day.
‎Let's just keep it between us for now.
‎Promise you'll do that.
Subtitle translation by: Lili Morita